The Balance Child and Learning to Enjoy Life
平衡的孩子与学习享受生命
May I ask You what are the important points in the education of children?
请问 你在孩子的教育中什么是重点
You see, first if they get realization
你看 首先若他们获得了自觉
to get first time to that point of realization
在一开始便得到了觉醒
if they are already born realized there is no problem
如果他们是天生自觉的 没有问题
but if they are given realization
但是如果他们被给予自觉
then, you see, they start seeing from a different level. They become the spirit
然后 他们开始从一个不同的层次看 他们成为了灵
so their self-respect, you see, awaken
所以他们的自尊 唤醒了
Such children behave in a very dignified, elderly manner, you see.
这些孩子的行为有尊严 成熟
They talk in a very elderly manner
他们用成熟的方式说话
and they give solutions of all kinds, you see
并且他们给出各种解决方案
and they are tremendous people
他们是伟大的人
But we have to guide them properly by our own behavior
但是我们必须言传身教恰当的引导他们
how we behave. The greatest thing is, how we behave
最伟大的事是 我们如何行事
that’s how the children learn.
那是孩子学习的
We put the children certain to some tests, how they are
我们会给孩子些测试 看他们如何
We find out if they have any physical problems; we cure them
我们发现 如果他们身体有问题 我们治疗他们
They have mental problem; we cure them
他们有心理问题 我们治疗他们
If they have any other problem, social problem or anything
如果他们有任何其他问题 社会问题 或其他问题
we try to help them out
我们试图帮助他们摆脱困难
so that basically if a human being is all right in the childhood
所以基本上如果一个人在童年是好的
then fundamentals are all right for the child. The foundation is laid down
那么那孩子的根基是好的 奠定了基础
Then to build a child up into a good quality is not difficult
那么把孩子塑造成好品质的人不难
So now we find great artists are there
我们发现那些伟大的艺术家
There are great musicians and at a very young age they started playing violin
那些伟大的音乐家 在很小的时候他们开始演奏小提琴
and suddenly they become very dynamic also and very humble
他们忽然变得很有活力并很谦卑
They are very humble and self-respectful and very well-behaved
他们很谦卑 有自尊 非常彬彬有礼
Surprising how the atmosphere is and how it works out
令人惊讶气氛是怎样的 并如何成就的
On the other day a lady asked me about the women
另一天一位女士问我关于妇女
and I told her that a woman’s power as a mother is very great
我告诉她一位女士作为一位母亲的力量是非常伟大的
She felt hurt about it. I didn’t mean that you should be just a mother
她对此感到受伤害 我不是说你应成为一个母亲
What I am saying, she is a mother; then she is compassionate
我是说 她是一个母亲 那她是慈悲的
she is kind, she is not aggressive like man
她是友善的 她不像男人那样好斗
That is a very big quality
那是非常伟大的品质
That is a very big power in a woman. That is what I was suggesting
那是女人非常伟大的力量 那是我建议的
that and that is what we have to understand, not to compete with men
我们必须明白的 不要和男人竞争
we have to understand that life has to be enjoyable
我们必须明白生活应该是令人愉快的
Life’s to be a blessing, not to be a misery
生活应当是被祝福的 不是不幸
We create our own miseries by these false ideas
我们给自己制造不幸 通过错误的想法
by our own conflictions we have in our mind
通过我们头脑中的冲突
mental projections we have in our mind
通过我们头脑中的心理投射
or our own obstinacy – whatever it is
或者我们自有的固执 无论是什么
All these things can be cured
所有这些可以被医治
if you take to Sahaja Yoga because you become a balanced person, level-headed, wise person
如果你练习霎哈嘉瑜伽 从而你成为一个平衡的人 高层次的人 聪明人
And you become a witness. The whole thing becomes like a show, like a drama
并且你成为一个静观者 整个事情变得象一个剧 象一出戏
and you become fearless and you start seeing the whole thing like a drama
并且你变得无畏 你开始如戏般的看待一切
and this is what a human being has to achieve
这就是一个人必须成就的
We talk of peace. We talk of no war. We talk of many things like this, you see
我们谈论和平 我们谈论不战争 我们谈论许多事
atomic bomb, this, that – all that are not going to work out
原子弹 这个 那个 所有这些无法解决
Only what is going to work out is the transformation of human beings
除非人类得到转化
If the human beings are transformed things will work out absolutely first class
如果人类被转化 事情将优先成就
Not only that, but that they will enjoy the bliss of life
不仅如此，而且他们将享受生命的祝福
We are missing the point altogether ! This is a very important thing
我们完全没有抓住要点 这是非常重要的事
that human beings must say, one thing
必须说人类
what have we achieved out of all these things?
在所有事中我们必须成就的一件事是什么呢？
Just for a minute to stop and think
只一分钟停下来思考